GABRIEL IDENYI

Python Developer

+234-807-250-2035 alexcharlz.github.io linkedin.com/in/gabriel-idenyi-9a1a62149 idenyigabriel@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Junior software engineer with over 2 years of active experience working with a wide range of front and backend technologies. I am happy to adapt to new technologies. The idea of joining your innovative and ever-growing organization is exciting. I will bring my experience and hard-work culture to contribute to your organization.

KEY SKILLS

- Fluent and experience in different programming languages; scripting, and objectoriented.
- Proficient at using Python, and JavaScript to deliver high-quality, clean, and well-structured production-ready code.
- I have an active working experience with a wide range of tools from the frontend, backend, and deployment phases of software development.
- Ability to develop project specifications from customer requirements.
- Ability to work independently with little or no assistance.
- Ability to identify, troubleshoot, and resolve existing issues.

EXPERIENCE

Uobis

Junior Python Developer | February 2020 - present

- Managed a process re-engineering an educational application to automate and improve processes and services; cutting down manual workload by more than 50% and improving overall user experience.
- Redesigned and currently managing a project with a few thousand active users.
- Spearheaded 3 projects through planning, development, and deployment phases, coordinated with the client, and developed project specifications through customer requirements.
- Proposed and implemented new features to improve current working processes and application performance.
- Designed full-stack web applications with Python, Django, HTML, CSS, Javascript, NextJs, React, and Flask.
- Authored over 6 functional applications using various technologies based on customer requirements.
- Trained and guided 3 new interns through introductory phases of web development using the python programming language.

90xtra

Website Designer | November 2018 - February 2020

- Set up and Launched website with WordPress.
- on-page SEO optimization, successfully increasing website daily hits to over 3000.
- Monitored its health status, identifying potential problems and implementing proper solutions to fix, and mitigate the reoccurrence of such problems in the future.

Atopet Automations Ltd

Embedded system intern | April 2018 to October 2018

- Embedded system design with c/c++, Arduino, esp 32, and Mbed.
- Teamed up with 2 other interns to develop a multi-gas leak detector for an expo.
- Built over 5 projects including an automated home prototype, blind man aid, obstacle avoidance system using PIR sensors and several more.
- Taught higher school students Arduino and the esp32 platform.

EDUCATION

2014 - 2021 | Michael Okpara University of Agriculture

Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Engineering.

• Graduated with an honours - second class upper degree.

2010 - 2014 | Gateway Schools

West African Senior School Certificate Examination.

- Served as Senior Prefect.
- Awarded Overall best graduating student.
- Multiple best-in-class awards.
- Awarded the most disciplined student.

SKILLS

- Python
- Django
- Flask
- HTML
- Postgres
- Linux
- Docker

- Javascript
- Next|s
- React
- CSS
- Git/Github
- C/C++

SOFT SKILLS

- Leadership
- Critical Thinker
- · Openness to criticism
- Decision-making

- Communication
- Creativity
- Resourcefulness